Lowell Nesbitt
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Correspondence and Subject Files, 1940-circa 1990s, Series 5:; (Boxes 5-12, 40, OV 51; 8.0 linear feet)
  - Exhibitions, 1981-1992, 5.3:
    - Humanist Icon (Box 11)
      - Loan Agreement, Jack Lenor Larsen, 1990 (Box 11)
      - Loan Agreement, Polly King, 1990 (Box 11)
      - Loan Agreement, Christopher Makos, 1990 (Box 11)
      - Loan Agreement, Jack Mitchell, 1990 (Box 11)
      - Loan Agreement, Malcolm Morley, 1990 (Box 11)
      - Loan Agreement, Lowell Nesbitt, 1990 (Box 11)
      - Loan Agreement, Mary Obering, 1990 (Box 11)
      - Loan Agreement, Anthony Quinn, 1990 (Box 11)
      - Loan Agreement, Madlyn Rhue, 1990 (Box 11)
      - Loan Agreement, Stillman Rockefeller, 1990 (Box 11)
      - Loan Agreement, Pauline Trigere, 1990 (Box 11)
      - Loan Agreement, Mehri Weil, 1990 (Box 11)
      - Wichita State University, 1990 (Box 11)
    - Landscapes and Gardens Show (1982), Andrew Crispo Gallery, 1982-1983 (Box 11)
    - Ohio Flower Shows (1983) Butler Institute, Youngstown University, 1982-1983, (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Oklahoma Arts Center (1983, 1985), 1983-1985, (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Temple University, 1986-1992 (Box 11)
    - Upcoming Exhibitions, 1981 (Box 11)
    - U. S. Department of State, Art in the Embassies Program (1985-1986), 1986-1990, (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Washington and Lee University (1983), 1983-1984 (Box 11)
    - World Wildlife Fund, U. S., 1981 (Box 11)
    - Oversized Humanist Icon Exhibition Collage of Works, 1990, (see Box 11) (Box OV 51)
  - Commissions, 1977-1993, 5.4:
    This subseries documents commissions Nesbitt undertook from a variety of individuals and organizations, including stamps for the United States Postal Service and the World Wildlife Fund.
    - Bartlestein, Mrs. Gordon, undated (Box 11)
    - Filming in Apartment, 1980-1981 (Box 11)
    - Flower Stamp Envelopes, 1981 (Box 11)
    - Harriet, Personal Treasures, 1977 (Box 11)
    - Hodges, Billy (Paul Frankel? Graphic Prints Contract?), undated (Box 11)
    - Horticultural Society (New York, NY), 1987 (Box 11)
    - Janis-Orange-Red Orchid, undated (Box 11)
    - People Magazine Article on Nesbitt's Pucci Mannequin Designs, 1990, (see OV 51) (Box 11)
    - Perry, Mrs., Apartment, 1978 (Box 11)
    - Plates, 1980-1981 (Box 11)
    - Pucci International, 1990 (Box 11)
    - Requests from Dealers and Individuals for Art, 1992-1993 (Box 11)
    - Rosenfeld, Michelle, 1978 (Box 11)
    - Rupert J. Smith, Inc. (New York, NY), 1988-1989 (Box 11)
    - Sid Peter Investments (Montfleury Wines, Arlington, VA), 1987-1988 (Box 11)
    - Thomas, Rusty, and National Wildflower Research Center, 1989 (Box 11)
    - Tom Jones Graphics, Greensboro, NC, 1980 (Box 12)
    - Two Wall Steet, New York, NY, 1984 (Box 12)
    - Uniclub, Credit Cards, New York, NY, 1988 (Box 12)
    - U. S. Opportunity Search, 1990 (Box 12)
    - U. S. Postal Service Postage Stamps (1981), 1980-1987 (Box 12)
    - U. S. Postal Service, Commemorative Flower Postage Stamps, Correspondence from Francesca, 1981, (see Box 40) (Box 12)
    - Warhol, Andy, Studio Purchased by Steven and Bernice Sohacki, 1982 (Box 12)
    - Wenniger Graphics (1985), Boston, MA, 1985-1988 (Box 12)
    - Wessel O'Connor Ltd., 1991 (Box 12)
    - Westheimer, Mrs. Jerome, 1978 (Box 12)
    - Wilm Fine Arts, Inc., 1992 (Box 12)
    - World Wildlife Fund, Lothar Kruger, 1989 (Box 12)
    - World Wildlife Fund, Stamps and Material, 1984, (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - People Magazine Article on Nesbitt's Pucci Mannequin, 1990, (see Box 11) (Box OV 51)
    - U. S. Postal Service Commemorative Flower Postage Stamps, Correspondence from Francesca, 1981, (see Box 12) (Box 40 (sol))
  - Committees, 1980-1992, 5.5:
    This subseries documents Nesbitt's work for several committees and fundraising events including the "Night of 100 Trees" to benefit artists with AIDS, and Project Rembrandt, the annual juried exhibition of the National Multiple Sclerosis Society for which Nesbitt was co-chairman. "Night of 100 Trees" material includes donation records and an invitation to the event designed by Nesbitt.
    - AIDS Benefit (1983), 1984 (Box 12)
    - "Night of 100 Trees," circa 1980s, (2 folders; see also OV 51) (Box 12)
    - F.I.T. Opening, undated (Box 12)
    - Multiple Sclerosis Society, New York Benefit (1987), 1987-1992, (4 folders) (Box 12)
    - Multiple Sclerosis, Committee Members Exhibition, 1990, (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - National Multiple Sclerosis Society, 1992 (Box 12)
    - Project Rembrandt, 1980-1990 (Box 12)
    - Project Rembrandt, Cemtie Show A F.I.T. 23 Artists, 1990 (Box 12)
    - Very Special Arts, N. Whalen, Hawthorne, NY, 1987-1988 (Box 12)
    - Night of 100 Trees, Donations, circa 1980s, (see also Box 12) (Box OV 51)
  - Legal/Subject Files, 1978-1991, 5.6:
    This subseries contains legal records including correspondence between Nesbitt and his lawyers.
    - Fraud, undated (Box 12)
    - Lawyers, NY Tenzer, Greenblatt, Fallon, and Kaplan-Alan Brockman, 1978-1985 (Box 12)
    - Marigold Goldberg, 1980 (Box 12)
    - Linda L. Longo-Muth, 1991 (Box 12)
    - Santa Fe Festival Theatre Company, 1980 (Box 12)
- Business and Financial Records, circa 1910-1993, Series 6:; (Box 12-14; 2.0 linear feet)
  This series documents business transactions involving Nesbitt's artwork and includes insurance, banking, shipping, payroll and tax records. It contains lists of his artwork available for sale with prices and other details concerning sales and consignments. There is a folder titled "Teaching List" that includes details of Nesbitt's lecture carousel and price lists. Also found here are records documenting Nesbitt's real estate purchases and records on donations he made to various charitable organizations.
  - List of Complete Works, Graphics (duplicate), undated, (5 folders) (Box 12)
  - Partial List of Artwork (catalogue duplicates), undated (Box 12)
  - List of Complete Paintings and Drawings (duplicate catalogue), undated, (2 folders) (Box 12)
  - Teaching List, undated (Box 12)
  - Master List of Prints and Available Graphics, circa 1980-1990 (Box 12)
  - Paintings In and Out of Studio (original order), undated, (8 folders) (Box 12)
  - Silkscreens and Lithographs, circa 1963-1981, (8 folders) (Box 13)
  - Art Sales, Bills, Invoices, circa 1987 (Box 13)
  - Receipts, In and Out, 1975-1979, (4 folders) (Box 13)
  - Artwork Sales, 1980-1992, (8 folders) (Box 13)
  - Artwork Receipts, 1988-1990, (2 folders) (Box 13)
  - Art-Related Bills and Invoices, 1983-1990, (2 folders) (Box 13)
  - Artwork Billing Forms, 1977-1981 (Box 13)
  - Pucci Invoice, 1992 (Box 13)
  - Price List of Art, 1980-1990 (Box 13)
  - Art Supply Receipts, 1979-1993, (17 folders) (Box 13)
  - Receipts, Art-Related Insurance, Invoices, 1982 (Box 13)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank Deposit Slips, 1977-1985, (5 folders) (Box 13)
  - Donations, 1970-1991, (5 folders) (Box 13)
  - Restoration Insurance, 1975-1980 (Box 13)
  - Insured Prints Damaged, 1980 (Box 13)
  - Random House, 1992 (Box 13)
  - Legal, Will and Courtcase Receipts, 1979 (Box 13)
  - James H. Benner, Insurance Services, 1967 (Box 13)
  - Insurance, Home, 1980, (2 folders) (Box 13)
  - Delivery Slips, 1980, (3 folders) (Box 14)
  - Shipping, W. R. Keating Co., 1980 (Box 14)
  - Shipping (Art in Embassies), 1989-1990 (Box 14)
  - Shipping Bills, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Paid Bills, Art and House, 1980, (3 folders) (Box 14)
  - Financial Statement 4th Quarter for Building, 1992 (Box 14)
  - Stoneleigh House, Tax, 1991 (Box 14)
  - Stoneleigh Bills, Not to be Paid, 1988 (Box 14)
  - Citibank Loan (Equity), Susan Bailey, 555 LaGuardia, NY, 1987-1988, (3 folders) (Box 14)
  - Real Estate Information (1983), 1981-1985 (Box 14)
  - Rental, 1970 (Box 14)
  - Home Furnishing, 1979 (Box 14)
  - House-Construction, Insurance, 1975-1976, (2 folders) (Box 14)
  - Entertainment Parties, 1980s, 1980 (Box 14)
  - Frank Nesbitt, 1947 (Box 14)
  - Income Statement, 1980 (Box 14)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1975 (Box 14)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1984 (Box 14)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1987 (Box 14)
  - Cash Receipts Ledger, 1982 (Box 14)
  - Financial Ledger, 1986 (Box 14)
  - Payroll and Bills Ledger, 1980 (Box 14)
  - Payroll and Bills Ledger, 1983 (Box 14)
  - Payroll Ledger, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Payroll, 1988 (Box 14)
  - Payroll and Disbursement Journal, 1989 (Box 14)
  - Payroll Ledger, 1990 (Box 14)
  - Payroll Ledger, 1991 (Box 14)
  - Stock Certificates Belonging to Nesbitt's Mother, circa 1910 (Box 14)
  - Stock Statements, Drexel, Burnham Lambert, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 14)
  - Tax, undated (Box 14)
- Artwork, circa 1948-1989, Series 7:; (Boxes 15-16, 41-42, OVs 52, 55; 2.0 linear ft.)
  This series is arranged as 2 subseries:
  7.1: Artwork by Nesbitt, circa 1948-1980s
  7.2: Artwork by Others, 1980-1989
  - Artwork by Nesbitt, 1948-circa 1980s, 7.1:
    This subseries contains a range of artwork by Nesbitt including collages incorporating leaves, flowers and found objects; drawings with subjects such as dancers, statues and flowers; paintings in gouache; prints including a copper plate; and sketchbooks including sketches of Nesbitt's travels to Egypt, Italy and elsewhere.
    - Artwork, Flower, undated, (see Box 41) (Box 15)
    - Baptism Window Design for St. Marylebone Church, undated (Box 15)
    - Collage Book, undated (Box 15)
    - Color Chart, undated (Box 15)
    - Copper Plate, undated (Box 15)
    - Drawing, "Welcome to Treasure Island," undated, (See OV 52) (Box 15)
    - Magazine Cutout Flowers on a Box, undated, (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Painting on Board, undated (Box 15)
    - Panel Book, undated (Box 15)
    - Print, undated (Box 15)
    - Print Fragment, 1979 (Box 15)
    - Print, Lithograph of Rose, 1973, (See OV 55) (Box 15)
    - Print of Bird, undated (Box 15)
    - Sketchbook, undated (Box 15)
    - Sketchbook, 1955 (Box 15)
    - Sketchbook I, undated (Box 15)
    - Sketchbook II, undated, (see Box 42) (Box 15)
    - Sketchbook III, undated (Box 15)
    - Sketchbook IV, undated, (see Box 42) (Box 15)
    - Sketchbook V, 1980 (Box 15)
    - Sketchbook VI, undated, (see Box 42) (Box 15)
    - Sketchbook VII, 1953 (Box 15)
    - Sketchbook VIII, Tyler School of Fine Art, 1954 (Box 15)
    - Sketchbook, Ballet, circa 1948, (see Box 42) (Box 15)
    - Sketchbook, Blank, undated (Box 16)
    - Sketchbook, Pen and Ink Drawings of Figures, Bird and Abstract, Flower Drawings, circa 1950s-1980s, (see Box 42) (Box 16)
    - Artwork, Flower, undated, (see Box 15) (Box 41 (sol))
    - Sketchbook, II, undated, (see Box 15) (Box 42 (sol))
    - Sketchbook, IV, undated, (see Box 15) (Box 42 (sol))
    - Sketchbook, VI, undated, (see Box 15) (Box 42 (sol))
    - Sketchbook, Ballet, circa 1948, (see Box 16) (Box 42 (sol))
    - Sketchbook, Pen and Ink Drawings of Figures, Bird and Abstract, Flower Drawings, circa 1950s-1980s, (see Box 16) (Box 42 (sol))
    - Drawing, "Welcome to Treasure Island," undated, (see Box 15) (Box 52 (OV))
    - Print, Lithograph of Rose, 1973, (see Box 15) (Box 55 (OV))
  - Artwork by Others, 1980-1989, 7.2:
    - Collage by Ray Johnson, undated (Box 16)
    - Drawing of a Record from Bill, 1978 (Box 16)
    - Print, "Ariadne," by Will Barnet, 1980 (Box 16)
    - Prints by Marco, 1989 (Box 16)
    - Sketch, "A Carpet Line Starring Lowell Nesbitt" by Everds, undated (Box 16)
    - Unidentified from Friends, undated (Box 16)
- Source Material, 1965-circa 1990s, Series 8:; (Boxes 16-26, 43-45, OV 53; 12.0 linear ft.)
  This series contains source material used by Nesbitt and documents his method of gathering photographs and magazine clippings and arranging them as collages on cardboard prior to painting. Groupings of source material reflect the range of Nesbitt's subject matter and include nudes, fruits and vegetables, flowers, landscapes, bridges, buildings and ruins, space, windows, easels, dogs and other animals and shoes. There is also a group of photographs of studios of artists including those of Alex Katz, Jasper Johns, Robert Indiana, Claes Oldenburg, and Andy Warhol.
  - Nudes, 1969-1988, (2 folders; see also Box 43) (Box 16)
  - Fruit and Vegetables, 1974-1988, (13 folders; see also Box 43) (Box 16)
  - Fruit and Vegetables, 1977-1980, (9 folders) (Box 17)
  - Flowers, 1970-1990, (16 folders; see also Box 43) (Box 17)
  - Flowers, 1965-circa 1990s, (25 folders; see also Boxes 43-44) (Box 18)
  - Flowers, 1966-1980, (20 folders; see also Box 45) (Box 19)
  - Flowers, circa 1970s-1987, (18 folders) (Box 20)
  - Flowers, 1976-1987, (4 folders) (Box 21)
  - Landscapes, 1974-1990, (8 folders; see also OV 53) (Box 21)
  - Caves and Miscellaneous, 1971-1989, (12 folders; see also Boxes 43-44) (Box 21)
  - Artist Studios, 1972-1976, (7 folders; see also Box 45) (Box 21)
  - Artist Studios, circa 1970s, (8 folders; see also Boxes 43, 45) (Box 22)
  - Bridges and Buildings, 1974-1978, (6 folders) (Box 22)
  - Studio, Windows, Easels, 1967-1977, (15 folders) (Box 22)
  - Studio, Windows, Easels, 1967-1977, (10 folders; see also Box 43) (Box 23)
  - Space Materials, 1969-circa 1970s, (5 folders) (Box 23)
  - Ruins, 1971-1987, (11 folders) (Box 23)
  - Ruins, circa 1970s, (2 folders) (Box 24)
  - Dogs and Animals, 1974-1986, (15 folders) (Box 24)
  - Sheet Series, 1971-1979, (4 folders) (Box 24)
  - Shoes, 1973-1980, (19 folders) (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous Oversized Material, 1967-1989, (30 folders) (Box 26)
  - Oversized Material, Nudes, 1985, 1972, (see also Box 16) (Box 43 (sol))
  - Oversized Material, Fruit and Vegetables, 1974-1979, (see also Box 16) (Box 43 (sol))
  - Oversized Material, Flowers, 1970-1987, (see also Boxes 17-18) (Box 43 (sol))
  - Oversized Material, Caves and Miscellaneous, undated, (see also Box 21) (Box 43 (sol))
  - Oversized Material, Artist Studios, 1974, (see also Boxes 21-22) (Box 43 (sol))
  - Oversized Material, Studio, Windows and Easels, 1972, (see also Box 23) (Box 43 (sol))
  - Oversized Material, Flowers, 1983-1987, (see also Box 18) (Box 44 (sol))
  - Oversized Material, Caves and Miscellaneous, 1983-1989, (see also Box 21) (Box 44 (sol))
  - Oversized Material, Flowers, 1974, 1980, (see also Box 19) (Box 45 (sol))
  - Oversized Material, Artist Studios, 1972, (see also Boxes 21-22) (Box 45 (sol))
  - Oversized Material, Landscapes, 1974, (see also Box 21) (Box OV 53)
- Photographs and Audiovisual Records, circa 1903-circa 1990s, Series 9:; (Boxes 16-26, 43-45, OV 53; 12.0 linear ft.)
  This series is arranged into 5 subseries:
  9.1: Photographs of Artwork, 1960-circa 1980s
  9.2: Personal Photographs, circa 1960s-circa 1990s
  9.3: Audiovisual Material, circa 1970s-circa 1980s
  9.4: Photograph Albums, circa 1903-1990s
  9.5: Slides, circa 1960s-circa 1980s
  - Photographs of Artwork, 1960-circa 1980s, 9.1:
    This subseries contains photographs of a wide range of Nesbitt's artwork. Photographs of his "autobiographical series" include subjects such as bottles, clothes, dogs, easels, hats, shoes, studios, and bridges. Photographs of flower paintings include paintings of irises, orchids, roses, tulips and violets, and photographs of his "Electric Series" include subjects such as daffodils, dahlias, lilies, poppies, roses and tulips.
    For additional photographs of artwork by Nesbitt see 9.4: Photograph Albums.
    - Autobiographical Series, circa 1960s-circa 1970s, (15 folders) (Box 27)
    - Flower Paintings, 1964-1973, (5 folders) (Box 27)
    - Flowers, Electric Series, circa 1970s, (11 folders) (Box 27)
    - Landscapes, Cave, Lunar Land, Ruins and Animals, circa 1960s-circa 1970s, (15 folders) (Box 27)
    - Space, circa 1960s-circa 1970s, (2 folders) (Box 27)
    - X-Ray Figures, 1960-circa 1970s, (8 folders) (Box 27)
    - X-Ray Figures, circa 1960s-circa 1970s, (6 folders) (Box 28)
    - Other Artwork and Miscellaneous, circa 1960s-circa 1980s, (61 folders) (Box 28)
  - Personal Photographs, circa 1960s-circa 1990s, 9.2:
    This subseries includes photographs of Nesbitt, his family, friends, colleagues and dogs. There are also photographs of male nudes and of Nesbitt with his artwork or posing with some of his subjects, in addition to photographs of Nesbitt in his studio.
    Also found here are photographs of Nesbitt and others, including Louise Nevelson, Gloria Steinem and Alfred Hitchcock, taken by photographer Jack Mitchell. A personal friend of Nesbitt, Mitchell had a solo exhibition titled Artist Lowell Nesbitt at the Butler Institute of American Art in 1982, and took many press photographs of Nesbitt. There are also several additional photographs taken by others including one by Robert Indiana, and seven folders of photographs of artwork by others.
    - Personal, 1976, undated, (4 folders) (Box 28)
    - Personal, circa 1960s-circa 1980s, (79 folders; see also Boxes 46-47, OVs 51, 57-58) (Box 29)
    - Personal, circa 1970s-1980s, (8 folders; see also Boxes 46-47) (Box 30)
    - Artwork by Others, 1963-1989, (7 folders; see also OV 58) (Box 30)
    - Photographs by Others (Box 30)
      - Indiana, Robert, "For Lowell from Robert Indiana," circa 1970s (Box 30)
      - Mitchell, Jack, 1969-circa 1990s, (27 folders; see also Box 47, OV 58) (Box 30)
      - Raymond, Lilo, "Michael," 1974 (Box 30)
      - Tighe, Mike, 1976 (Box 30)
      - Weisond, D., undated (Box 30)
  - Oversized Photographs by Others, Jack Mitchell, 1969, (see also Box 30) (Box 41 (sol))
  - Oversized Personal Photographs, undated, (2 folders; see also Boxes 28-30) (Box 46 (sol))
  - Oversized Personal Photographs, undated, (see also Boxes 28-30) (Box 47 (sol))
  - Oversized Photographs by Others, Jack Mitchell, 1969-1984, (11 folders; see also Box 30) (Box 47 (sol))
  - Oversized Personal Photographs, undated, (2 folders; see also Boxes 28-30) (Box OV 51)
  - Oversized Personal Photographs, undated, (see also Boxes 28-30) (Box OV 57)
  - Oversized Personal Photographs, undated, (13 folders; see also Boxes 28-30) (Box OV 58)
  - Oversized Photographs of Artwork by Others, 1963, (see also Box 30) (Box OV 58)
  - Oversized Photographs by Others, Jack Mitchell, 1982, (see also Box 30) (Box OV 58)
  - Audiovisual Material, circa 1970s-circa 1980s, 9.3.:
    This subseries contains audiocassettes, videocassettes and films relating to Nesbitt and other artists including Keith Haring. It includes the film "The Ruins," shot in Nesbitt's studio and a film of Nesbitt painting a book mobile with "electric flowers" for the Miami-Dade Public Library.
    - Audiocassette, WBAA Interview Segment B., undated (Box 31)
    - Audiocassettes, 2 not labeled, 1 "Lowell Nesbitt Taped Conversations with Dean Farrell Cano," undated, (3 cassettes) (Box 31)
    - Videocassette, "Keith Haring" by Broad Street Productions, 1988 (Box 31)
    - Videocassette, "Keith Haring Slides 4," undated (Box 31)
    - Videocassette, "Project Rembrandt," undated (Box 31)
    - Film, "Lowell Nesbitt Paints the Artmobile," undated (Box 31)
    - Film, "Artmobile," Miami-Dade Public Library, 1976 (Box 31)
    - Film, "The Ruins," "Film from John," undated (Box 31)
  - Photograph Albums, circa 1903-1990s, 9.4:
    Albums contain both personal photographs and photographs of artwork.
    - Trip Abroad, undated (Box 31)
    - Trips, undated (Box 31)
    - Trips, Flowers, Animals, undated (Box 31)
    - Album I, circa 1903-1970s (Box 32)
    - Album II, 1930-1950s (Box 32)
    - Album III, 1950-1970s (Box 32)
    - Album IV, 1960s-1970s (Box 32)
    - Album V, 1980s-1990s (Box 32)
    - X-Ray Figures, 1963-1971 (Box 33)
    - Stair Exterior, 1965-1971 (Box 33)
    - Flowers, 1964-1970 (Box 33)
    - Nude Figure, 1969-1977 (Box 33)
    - Autobiographical Series, 1973-1976 (Box 33)
    - X-Ray Flowers, 1963-1973 (Box 33)
    - Flowers (1973), 1971-1974 (Box 34)
    - Studios, Computers, Moon, 1967-1972 (Box 34)
    - Landscapes, Caves, 1965-1983 (Box 34)
    - Loft Photos, undated (Box 34)
    - Flowers, 1975-1978 (Box 34)
    - Autobiographical Series, 1973-1975 (Box 34)
    - House with Artwork, Artwork, undated (Box 35)
    - Ruins, 1970-1972 (Box 35)
    - Electric Flowers, 1974 (Box 35)
    - Stairs Interior, 1965-1971 (Box 35)
  - Slides, circa 1960s-circa 1980s, 9.5:
    Material found here is a combination of slides of artwork and personal slides in addition to slides of nudes by Jack Mitchell. Slides contain images of paintings, sculpture, Nesbitt's "autobiographical" and "retrospective" series, landscapes, and stills of the Humanist Icon and Secret Garden exhibitions. Many of the slides found here were used by Nesbitt for lectures that were originally stored in slide carousels. Also found here are images stored on several slide viewers.
    - Slides 1-13, undated (Box 35)
    - Slides 14-21, undated (Box 36)
    - Slides 22-28, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 36)
    - Slides 29-31, undated (Box 36)
    - Slides 33-38, undated (Box 36)
    - Slides 39-46, undated (Box 36)
    - Slides 47-55, undated (Box 36)
- Printed Material, circa 1960s-circa 1990s, Series 10:; (Boxes 37-39, 45, OVs 48-50, 54, 56, 60; 3.05 linear feet)
  This series includes exhibition announcements and catalogs, clippings concerning exhibitions of Nesbitt's work and articles about his home, as well as posters relating to commissions Nesbitt undertook, gallery openings, and fundraisers in which he was involved.
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1965-1990, (31 folders) (Box 37)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1964-circa 1990s, (9 folders) (Box 38)
  - Clippings and Magazine Articles on Nesbitt, circa 1960s-circa 1990s, (33 folders; see also Box 45) (Box 38)
  - Clippings and Magazine Articles on Nesbitt, 1968-circa 1990s, (30 folders; see also Box 45) (Box 39)
  - Posters, 1969-1990, (see OV 48) (Box 39)
  - Posters, 1974-circa 1980s, (see OV 49) (Box 39)
  - Posters, 1981-1982, (see OV 50) (Box 39)
  - Posters, 1972-1984, (see OV 54) (Box 39)
  - Posters, 1973-1983, (see OV 56 and OV 60) (Box 39)
  - Licht Editions: Serigraph Calendar, 1972, (see OV 60) (Box 39)
  - Oversized Clippings and Magazine Articles on Nesbitt, Corcoran Mapplethorpe Exhibit, 1989, (3 folders; see also Boxes 38-39) (Box 45 (Sol))
  - Oversized Clippings and Magazine Articles on Nesbitt, circa 1970s-1980s, (see also Boxes 38-39) (Box 45 (Sol))
  - Oversized Clippings and Magazine Articles on Nesbitt, J. Burckhardt Reproductions on Prints, undated, (see also Boxes 38-39) (Box 45 (Sol))
  - Oversized Clippings and Magazine Articles on Nesbitt, Project Rembrandt Calendar, 1994, (see also Boxes 38-39) (Box 45 (Sol))
  - Oversized Posters, 1969-1990, (16 posters; see Box 39) (Box 48 (OV))
  - Oversized Posters, 1974-circa 1980s, (11 posters; see Box 39) (Box 49 (OV))
  - Oversized Posters, 1981-1982, (21 posters; see Box 39) (Box 50 (OV))
  - Oversized Posters, 1981-1982, (12 posters; see Box 39) (Box 54 (OV))
  - Oversized Posters, 1973-1983, (10 posters; see Box 39) (Box 56 (OV))
  - Oversized Licht Editions Serigraph Calendar, 1972, (see Box 39) (Box 60 (OV))
- Scrapbooks, 1964-1992, Series 11:; (BV's 61-88; 5.0 linear feet)
  The scrapbooks in this series contain invitations, photographs, newspaper clippings and other printed material related to exhibitions, photographs of artwork, Nesbitt's studio, events and parties he attended and hosted, and exhibition openings.
  - Landscapes, undated (Box 61 (BV))
  - Nudes, undated (Box 62 (BV))
  - Studio and Artwork, undated (Box 63 (BV))
  - "Lowell Nesbitt" Scrapbooks, 1964-1992, (25 scrapbooks) (Box 64-88 (BVs))